Richard Tuttle

(208) 850 – 9424 | richardtuttle@me.com | Tampa, FL LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/richard-tuttle | Portfolio: rtuttlecoder.github.io

Senior Full-stack Web Developer

A senior-level Web Developer and technologically creative person possessing the ability to diagnose and solve problems in a technology-driven environment who also loves developing impactful web experiences; and, a team player who can deliver world-class, user-centered products and services.

SKILLS

- Program Management
- Full Life Cycle Design
- Product Development
- Agile/Scrum
- Remote Working/Tools
- Problem Solving

- ADA/ARIA Compliancy
- Instructional Design
- WordPress expert
- Responsive Design
- Mobile-first Design

Platforms, CMSes, and Frameworks

Vue/Nuxt, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Jekyll, WordPress, React, Express.js, ZenCart, openCart, Joomla, Magento, MongoDB, Builder, Prismic, Contentful

Tools

Git, Pug, EJS, Flexbox, Authorize.net, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Illustrator, MS Office Suite, Google Analytics, WHM, cPanel, Docker, Sketch, AWS, TeamViewer, LogMeIn, ScreenConnect, Webpack, Babel, Node, Zoom, Figma

Languages

HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Typescript, PHP, MySQL, XML, Python, Liquid, Java, JSON

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

22squared, Atlanta, GA Senior Developer (Remote) 2020 - present

- Conceptualize and develop client projects throughout the creation cycle
- Work with a wide-array of technologies in evaluating and scoping projects
- Utilize modern frameworks and technology to give a great end-user experience
- Mentor junior-level Developers on their projects and skills
- Work with Project Managers and QA analysts to bring projects to complete fruition
- Utilize agile development techniques to work through project timelines
- Troubleshoot, debugged, and solved cross-browser issues
- Leveraged tools for assessing ADA and usability compliance
- Train staff and client, as needed, on the various technology creations

NIC, Inc. / Access Idaho, Boise, ID Lead Front-end & WordPress Developer (partial Remote)

2017 - 2020

- Assisted in the maintenance and enhancements of Idaho.gov
- Customized Idaho's WordPress library of services
- Built websites for customers based on Idaho templates
- Maintained and updated Idaho State templates and documentation according to Idaho standards and latest information
- Met with stakeholders to conceptualize and develop interactive content, generated concepts/mockups, gathered information and created websites based on customer needs
- Trained/assisted customers in maintaining their own WordPress websites
- Provided continued support for sites already launched via troubleshooting, bug fixes, instructional help, etc.
- Assisted in user-interface design and testing of online applications and websites
- Troubleshoot, debugged, and solved cross-browser issues
- Leveraged tools for assessing ADA and usability compliance
- Assisted with user research and usability testing efforts

Richard Tuttle | richardtuttle@me.com | rtuttlecoder.github.io | Page Two

- Developed & built static sites utilizing templating frameworks
- Contributed creatively to the growth of the company

Northwind, Inc., Boise, ID Sr. Web Developer (Remote)

2011 - 2017

- Built websites for B2C, B2B, and Nonprofit customers utilizing various platforms: WordPress, Joomla, Drupal, ZenCart, openCart, Magento, as well as custom developed/programmed sites
- Provided continued support for customers via troubleshooting, bug fixes, instructional help, etc.
- Aided in the corporation's increase in profit margin by 58%

PUBLICATIONS

- Technical proofer for Computer Networking Technology, 2nd Ed. Delmar Publishing
- Proofer for *PHP for the World Wide Web: Visual QuickStart Guide*, 2nd Ed. Peachpit Press "Working the Web: a four-part series" for The Newsletter
- Technical proofer for Computer Networking Technology Delmar Publishing
- "Where Web Design Begins" for HomeBizAdvice "Website Maintenance Tutorial" for HTMLCenter
- Principle author of Pure HTML: a reference Macmillan Computer Publishing (Sams.Net)

(more titles available upon request)

EDUCATION and CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor Degree - University of Maryland

Associate Degree - Portland Community College

Certified "Google Analytics Advisor"

Certified "Authorize.net Developer"

Idaho Limited Occupational Specialist certification, endorsed for Information/Communication Technology

Technical Conference Workshops/Tutorials: OSCON, Fluent, WebConf, NuxtCon, VueCon, etc.